

# J. DREW SMITH

## **PORTFOLIO**

jdrewsmith.com

#### **EMAIL**

joseph.drew.smith@gmail.com

#### **PHONE**

(801) 874-4988

#### **ABOUT**

I am committed to improving lives through design. My experience as an Industrial Designer taught me how empathize with users and recognize their pain points. My experience designing software has taught me how to think systematically, to validate designs through testing, and embrace lean UX in an agile environment.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **IBM CLOUD - UX DESIGNER**

Austin, Texas

Design security features and services which are distributed through the Bluemix and SoftLayer Platforms. June 2015 - Present

## **FAHRENHEIT DESIGN - ID INTERN**

Austin, Texas

Worked closely with the Dell Enterprise designers, other smaller local startups, and internal projects. June 2014 - September 2014

# WHIRLPOOL ADVANCED DESIGN - ID INTERN

Chicago, Illinois

Involved in all parts of design process for blue-sky products as the only intern on the advanced design team. January 2014 - June 2014

# **BYU ATHLETIC DEPARTMENT - GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

Provo, Utah

Created marketing material for print, web, social media, and branding installations in the athletic facilities.

June 2013 - January 2014

# **BYU LEARNING SUITE - UI/UX DESIGNER**

Provo, Utah

Designed new workflow, features, and UI elements for BYU's internal learning management software. June 2012 - April 2013

## **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

From June 2015 to September 2015

IBM Design Bootcamp

IBM Design Austin.

From September 2009 to April 2015

BFA in Industrial Design.
Brigham Young University - Provo, Utah.

From January 2015 to April 2015

UX Design Apprenticeship on development of learning simulation software.

Professor Derek Hansen, Brigham Young University - Provo.

From September 2014 to April 2015

Design Research Assistant on "Fragrance and Color" study.

Professor Bryan Howell, Brigham Young University - Provo, Utah.

From August 2013 to September 2013

International Study Abroad.

Milan, Italy; Paris, France; London, England.